{
    "id": "2159b0a43b4649ae92407e4f1ac1b3c7",
    "title": "Degrees Of Comparison",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He is ……………………….. runner of them all.",
            "description": "The superlative is used to compare a person or thing with the whole group he/she/it belongs to.",
            "answers": [
                "fastest",
                "faster",
                "the fastest",
                "the faster"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Susie and Janet are both pretty girls, but I think Susie is …………………………….. of the two.",
            "description": "When a group has just two members, the comparative is used instead of the superlative.",
            "answers": [
                "the pretty",
                "the prettier",
                "the prettiest"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Can you talk ……………………………..?",
            "description": "Comparative and superlative adverbs are usually made with more and most.",
            "answers": [
                "slowlier",
                "more slowly",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Can you come ………………………………?",
            "description": "Adverbs that have the same form as adjectives form their comparatives and superlatives with –er and –est.",
            "answers": [
                "more early",
                "earlier",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "That was ……………………………. kind of you.",
            "description": "When most means very, it is used without the.",
            "answers": [
                "most",
                "the most",
                "the more"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She is ……………………………… her father than her mother.",
            "description": "The word like forms its comparatives and superlatives with more and most.",
            "answers": [
                "more like",
                "liker",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She looks just ………………………….. her mother.",
            "description": "We use like before a noun and as before a clause.",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "like",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He fought …………………………. a lion.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "like",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I get up at 30 …………………………. my mother does.",
            "description": "We use like before a noun and as before a clause.",
            "answers": [
                "like",
                "as",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He looks …………………………….. younger than her.",
            "description": "We cannot use very to modify comparative adjectives.",
            "answers": [
                "very",
                "much",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She is ………………………….. woman I have ever known.",
            "description": "Superlatives are more common with words like ever. ",
            "answers": [
                "the best",
                "the good",
                "the better"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Mandarin is …………………………….. more difficult than Hindi.",
            "description": "Very cannot be used with comparatives.",
            "answers": [
                "much",
                "far",
                "very"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}